[ slow music playing ]
[ clock ticking ]
- [ leaves rustling ] - [ ticking grows louder ]
11 : 55 ... almost midnight .
Enough time for one more story ,
one more story before twelve .
[ ominous music playing ]
Just to keep us warm .
In five minutes , it will be the 21st of April .
One hundred years ago , on the 21st of April ,
out on the waters around Spivey Point ,
a small clipper ship Drew toward land .
Suddenly , out of the night , the fog rolled in .
For a moment , they could see nothing ,
not a foot ahead of them .
And then they saw a light .
By God , it was a fire burning on the shore ,
strong enough to penetrate the swirling mist .
They steered a course toward the light ,
but it was a campfire like this one .
The ship crashed against the rocks .
The hull sheared in two .
The mast snapped like a twig ,
and the wreckage sank with all the men aboard .
At the bottom of the sea
lay the Elizabeth Dane with her crew ,
their lungs filled with salt water ,
their eyes open and staring into the darkness .
And above , as suddenly as it had come ,
the fog lifted , receded back across the ocean ,
[ almost whispering ] and never came again .
But it is told by the fishermen
and their fathers and grandfathers
that when the fog returns to Antonio Bay ,
the men at the bottom of the sea ,
out in the water by Spivey Point ,
will rise up and search for the campfire
that led them to their dark and icy death .
[ bell tolling ]
12 : 00 ,
the 21st of April .
[ ominous piano music playing ]
- [ bell tolling ] - [ wind whistling loudly ]
[ crickets chirping ]
[ bell tolling ]
[ Stevie Wayne over radio ] It 's twelve midnight ,
and we just started the little witching hour .
This is Stevie Wayne , on top of the world tonight .
And I 'll be here right up until about 1 : 00 .
[ jazz playing ]
[ turns radio off ]
[ whistling ]
[ doors creaking ]
[ Bennett ] I 'm all through , Father .
Oh , thank you , Bennett .
Uh ... I won 't need you until 4 : 00 tomorrow , Bennett .
Yes , Sir .
Would you like something to keep you warm on the way home ?
No , thank you . Father , can I get paid ?
Why don 't you come in at , uh , 6 : 00
instead of 4 : 00 tomorrow ?
[ crickets chirping ]
Yes , Sir .
[ sighs ]
Uh , Bennett ? Eh , Bennett ?
- [ rustling sound ] - Bennett ?
Hello ?
[ jazz playing on the radio ]
Uh ...
[ ominous music playing together with jazz ]
[ jazz continues over radio ]
[ Stevie on the radio ] It 's 59 degrees outside .
And let me be the first to wish Antonio Bay a Happy Birthday .
We 're one hundred years old today .
The weatherman 's been trying to spoil it for us .
He says we may be in for some rain tonight .
But from where I 'm sitting , it looks like clear skies .
I think the weatherman 's been working too hard .
- Well , I 'll stay here for another hour ... - [ cats meow ]
just to see if he 's right .
And I 'm inviting you to stay here with me .
[ radio static ]
[ police radio ] Uh , there 's a cutter run aground over here on the east bay , over .
- [ static ] - Global 1X5 .
It 's the Lady Belle Pacific ,
serial number 024KL596 . Over .
Global 1X5 , the Lady Belle Pacific is sea worthy ,
no major damage .
Why don 't you send a tow on over here ,
about a quarter mile above the boatel . Over .
[ telephones ringing ]
[ ringing continues ]
[ coins clinking into change holders ]
[ ringing continues in distance ]
[ telephone ring winds down ]
[ squeaking ]
[ sweeping sounds ]
[ glass shatters ]
[ something crashes in distance ]
[ sign squeaking ]
[ buzzing lightly ]
[ crickets chirping ]
[ lights buzzing ]
[ beeping rhythmically ]
[ beeping continues ]
[ bell tolling loudly ]
[ crickets chirping ]
[ horns blowing ]
[ car alarm beeping ]
- [ noise dies down ] - [ dog barking ]
[ music playing ]
- [ ticking ] - [ radio playing ]
[ Stevie ] This is KAB , Antonio Bay , California .
Six minutes after midnight .
Haven 't heard from the weatherman yet ,
so I can 't say for sure about that rain ,
but there 's a full moon and no clouds in the sky .
[ soft jazz playing ]
I 'm Stevie Wayne .
And if you don 't have anything to do right now ,
I 'll be here playing music all through the witching hour .
Even if you do have something to do ,
keep me turned on for a while ,
and I 'll try my best to do the same for you .
OK !
- [ out of breath ] Hi . - Hi .
- How far you going ? - Other side of town .
That 's close enough .
- Make it ? - Yeah . Thank you .
- Sip ? - Thanks .
Listen , I never hitchhiked before .
I just really want to be careful .
Can I ask you something ?
- Sure . - Are you weird ?
Yes , I am .
Yes , I am weird .
- You are weird . You 're weird . - Yes .
Thank God you 're weird .
The last one I had was so normal , it was disgusting .
He picked me up in Santa Barbara .
By the time we got to Carmel he wanted to marry me .
Oh , yeah . I thought you never hitchhiked before .
Not before last week .
You 're my ...
thirteenth ride .
Oh , great . Weird and unlucky .
We 'll see .
Look out ! Oh !
[ tires screech ]
- Are you all right ? - I 'm fine .
- You 're sure ? - I 'm fine . I think so .
What the hell was - -
[ music playing on the radio ]
[ Stevie ] It 's exactly twelve minutes after midnight ,
and this is Stevie Wayne ,
- your night light , - Let 's get out of here .
around , until about ... 1 : 00 .
I 'm high tonight in the KAB lighthouse on Spivey Point .
And in case you 've forgotten , it 's April 21st .
And a Happy Birthday for Antonio Bay .
Now , there 's a celebration planned for tonight .
So if you 're so excited about it you can 't sleep ,
well , stay up with me ,
and I 'll figure out some way to keep you occupied .
Or not .
[ music playing on the radio ]
[ telephone rings ]
KAB .
Hi , sweetheart .
Hi , Dan . What have you got ?
Well , I 'm just calling to see if you 're lonely ,
if there 's anything I can do about it .
Never lonely , Dan .
I thought you were off work at 8 : 00 .
I changed shifts so I can make it to the big party tonight .
Will you be there ?
Well ... until I can talk someone else
into giving up city life for Antonio Bay , I 'm it .
And " it " means day and night .
Too much work .
Well , that 's what I get for owning a station .
And if you don 't tell me why you called in about 15 seconds ,
I 'm gonna have to hang up on you .
You want something to talk about ?
Anything .
I 've got a position on a trawler about ,
15 Miles out , called The Sea Grass .
And I 've got something on my scope ,
appears to be a fog bank .
Oh , it 's about 25 miles out ,
moving in their direction .
Thanks , Dan .
That 's worth about 10 seconds .
I 'm on the air . Bye .
[ line breaks ]
[ intro music ]
Ahoy , mateys . This is KAB , Antonio Bay .
Stevie Wayne here beaming a signal across the sea .
To the men on The Sea Grass ,
15 miles out tonight , a warm hello ,
and keep a watch out for that fog bank
heading in from the east .
In the meantime , relax with me while I play this song
from the Coupe de Villes ... dedicated just to you .
Boy , would I like to meet her .
I saw her at a grocery store one day .
- And ? - You would like to meet her .
She 's crazy . There 's no fog bank out there .
What do you know about her ?
- She owns that lighthouse . - I know that .
Her son plays little league with my kid brother .
She 's a mother ?
[ laughs ] I thought you were happily married .
- [ scoffs ] Not that happy . - There 's no fog bank out there .
Hey . There 's a fog bank out there .
All right . I 'm drunk enough .
Let 's go back .
All right , all right .
Al , come here .
- Just give him a hand . - Come here .
[ ominous music mixed with the radio ]
What was that ?
[ coughs ]
[ beeping ]
[ engine starts ]
[ buoy bell rings ]
Come here .
What was that ?
- [ engine shuts down ] - It 's the generator .
Wha - - wha - -
Al .
[ wood creaking ]
[ anchor chain rattles and splashes ]
It 's gone .
Hey , there was just a ship out there .
Al , listen .
Nothing .
- [ whispers ] Listen . - [ loudly ] Who 's there ?
[ whispers ] Who is that ?
[ wind blowing silently ]
Aah !
Al ! [ groans ]
[ screams ]
[ gasps ]
[ monitor beeping ]
Al , it 's right beside us .
[ ominous music playing silently ]
It 's big , Al . It 's a ship .
It 's a big ship !
- [ music grows louder ] - [ monitor beeping continues ]
What happened ? Did you get wet ?
[ choking sounds ]
[ fog horn ]
It 's 12 : 43 ...
and I 've got four in a row for you right here on KAB .
- [ click ] - [ slow music starts playing ]
Nothing but water , Stevie .
But it sure beats Chicago .
[ telephone rings ]
KAB .
I like what you said
but for your information , you lied .
The fog bank has moved due west
and probably missed the ship entirely .
Well , my gauges must be wrong .
I 've got a wind blowing due east .
Now , what kind of a fog blows against the wind ?
You got me .
I 'm not so sure I want you .
You 're just a voice on the phone .
And you 're just a voice on the radio . We 'd make a perfect couple .
You let me take you to dinner tonight , I 'll prove it to you .
Sorry , Dan .
My idea of perfection is a voice on the phone .
OK , mystery lady .
Good night .
- Not bad . - [ chuckles ]
I started a week ago in San Diego ,
right up the coast , five drawings a day .
It 'll probably take me a month to get to Vancouver ,
and if I can sell ' em for five bucks apiece , I 'll be rich .
[ laughs ] Yeah .
Cool .
- Can I ask you something ? - Sure .
- What 's your name ? - Elizabeth .
- Nick . - Hello , Nick .
Hi .
Is that where you 're from , San Diego ?
Wait a minute . You said , " can I ask you something ? "
Well , something to me means one thing . San Diego is two things .
OK .
Pasadena , and a lot of money .
Never a chance to do anything I wanna do .
Aww .
[ mockingly ] Aww .
What do you want to do ?
I don 't know .
That 's OK . Me neither .
I think I got to have this one . Can I buy it ?
Uh-uh . The drawing 's free .
[ rhythmical knocking on door ]
[ knocking continues ]
- [ knocking ] - [ clock ticking ]
[ clock chimes ]
[ ominous music grows louder ]
[ ominous music stops ]
[ music playing on the radio ]
[ Stevie ] It 's 1 : 00 , straight up ,
the end of the witching hour
and time for me to sign off .
[ dog barking in distance ]
So until tomorrow night , at 6 : 00 p.m. ,
when KAB comes back on the air ,
this is Stevie Wayne , your night light ,
hoping you have a nice rest of the night .
[ music fades out ]
- [ seagulls screeching ] - [ wind blowing ]
[ ominous music playing ]
[ frogs croaking ]
- [ music fades out ] - [ clock tolls ]
[ shouts ] Mom ! Hey , mom !
Mom !
Mom , come on . Get up . Look what I found .
Andy ... I love you ,
but sometimes you 're a real pain .
Sure , mom , but look it . First , it was a gold coin ,
and then it turned into this neat piece of wood .
- This is one of those times . - Uh-huh , but look at it , mom .
Good morning , Andrew . Did you have a nice time last night ?
Yeah . Old Mr. Machen told us ghost stories .
Did you thank Mrs. Kobritz for bringing you home ?
Yes , ma 'am . Mom , can I have a stomach pounder and a coke ?
- After lunch . - OK .
I 'm gonna go look for another one .
Maybe this time I can get the gold coin .
[ seagulls screeching ]
Where the hell is he ?
Rolled out of here at 4 : 15 yesterday .
- That 's the last I saw of him . - Al said 7 : 30 , right here .
Well , you know Al . If I were you , I 'd give myself - -
Did you call the coast guard , Hank ?
Nick , they probably got drunk last night .
- They 're still out there ... - No , he wouldn 't do that .
He 'd do anything .
Al and I got drunk so many times together , I can 't count ' em all ,
but we never got so shitfaced we couldn 't make it back in .
He 's too good a sailor to stay out there all night and not let somebody know .
- You sound like his wife . - Just his friend .
- You worry too much , Nick . - Yeah .
- Where are we going ? - I 'm going to talk Ashcroft
into taking out his boat and looking for The Sea Grass .
- Who 's Ashcroft ? - Someone who owes me a favor .
Can I come along ?
I thought you had to move on to Vancouver ?
- Eventually . - Yeah .
[ fanfare ]
The sheriff will drive his own car .
The mayor and his wife
are to be picked up at 6 : 45 and brought to the mayor 's box .
Then we 'll have speeches by the mayor , the sheriff , and me .
- Oh , do you have my notes ? - Yes , ma 'am .
Then we will pass out the candles and begin the procession .
Then I will go home and pass out .
I 'm almost afraid to look .
Well ...
[ man on P.A. ] Testing , testing .
- Not bad . Not bad at all . - A work of art .
Sandy , just be civil to me for another five hours .
That 's all I ask .
[ Mrs. Williams ] Let 's see now . Oh , the candles .
Did you order the candles ? What a thought , a candlelight
- procession with no candles . - [ sing-songy ] All taken care of .
And the promotional material ...
- Did you get that over to Stevie ? - Signed , sealed , and delivered .
Sandy , you can be a very annoying person at times ,
- but you do keep me together . - Thank you , Mrs. Williams .
[ classical music playing ]
[ changing station ]
[ man on the radio ] Spivey Point . As of 1 : 57 today ,
The Sea Grass had not responded to radio communication .
The coast guard has begun a sweep South from Watley ,
around Arcom Reef , and should be in the area of Spivey Point
in approximately one hour .
Repeating this bulletin from the coast guard ,
be on the look out for The Sea Grass , a 30-foot trawler ,
last seen approximately 15 miles east of Spivey Point .
If you sight this vessel , please notify the coast guard immediately .
- Nick , can I ask you a question ? - Yeah .
- Is it always like this ? - It 's always different .
- You 're worried , aren 't you ? - Yeah .
She can get real mean .
There .
[ Nick ] Oh , yeah .
Oh , yeah .
[ Mrs. Williams ] Well , if I can just get through the speeches without yawning .
- I couldn 't sleep last night . - [ Sandy ] Too excited ?
No . Al went out on his boat last night and didn 't come home .
- He still isn 't back . - Mrs. Williams !
I called the coast guard , and they said ,
" Oh , he might have had engine trouble . "
They said not to worry .
He was complaining about his boat last week .
Maybe you ought to go home .
Oh , that 's the last place I want to go .
My dog started to bark at 12 : 00 last night
and didn 't stop until 6 : 00 this morning .
What happened ?
He was pointed toward the ocean and growling .
What does that tell you ?
My dog goes crazy and decides to bark at the water .
I heard the church bells at midnight as I started to drift off to sleep ,
and suddenly , my car alarm went off for absolutely no reason .
- Really ? - Uh-huh .
Woke up the whole block . This town sits around for 100 years
and nothing happens , and then one night , the whole place falls apart .
Al ?
Take this line , too .
[ shouts ] Al ! Tommy ! Dick !
Cabin and steering house are empty .
Maybe somebody picked them up .
- There 's water in the generator . - But the deck is as dry as a bone .
[ ominous music playing ]
[ Mrs. Williams ] There you have it . My next project , restoration
of the Morgantown Road Cemetery . It 's historical .
- Our ancestors are buried here . - It 's gonna cost a lot .
Come on , Sandy . So ? This town should be proud of its past .
But trying to get anyone involved in community affairs is like pulling teeth .
Better get the estimates ready for the council meeting next month .
Yes , ma 'am .
Sandy , you 're the only person I know who can make
" yes , ma 'am " sound like " screw you . "
Yes , ma 'am .
Now , if we 'll just say a little prayer asking that he not be in his cups .
[ doors creaking ]
Not a good sign .
[ sing-songy ] Father Malone ? Father Malone !
[ doors creaking ]
- Hello ! - Another bad sign .
You try the study , and I 'll look up front .
Father Malone !
- Jesus ! - I 'm sorry , Mrs. Williams .
- Mrs. Williams ... - Are you all right ?
I have something to show you .
[ ominous music playing ]
" December 9 .
Met with Blake this evening for the first time .
He stood in the shadows
to prevent me from getting a clear look at his face .
What a vile disease this is .
He is a rich man with a cursed condition ,
but this does not prevent him from trying to better his situation
and that of his comrades at the colony . "
Every single gauge is broken .
- All the glass is shattered . - Remind you of something ?
- Last night . - Your truck .
Yeah . Yeah .
Thermometer 's broken .
The mercury 's stuck at 20 degrees .
There 's no water got in here ,
but something awful cold did .
" December 11 . Blake 's proposition is simple .
He wants to move off Tanzier Island
and relocate the entire colony just north of here .
He has purchased a clipper ship
called the Elizabeth Dane .
With part of his fortune
and asks only for permission to settle here .
I must balance my feelings of mercy and compassion
toward this poor man with my revulsion at the thought
of a leper colony only a mile distant . "
It 's rusted to the wall .
[ radio static ]
It was on .
- They drank a lot of beer last night . - Every night .
What 's it like ?
It 's always the same . Room starts spinning - -
I mean fishing .
[ clears throat ]
You fish .
The only thing I know about fishing is you use a lot of worms .
Hmm .
Salt water .
She was clean 2 nights ago . I checked her out myself .
And now it 's as if she 's been turned over in the water .
" April 20 . The six of us met tonight .
From midnight until 1 : 00 ,
we planned the death of Blake and his comrades .
I tell myself that Blake 's gold will allow the church to be built
and our small settlement to become a township ,
but it does not soothe the horror that I feel
being an accomplice to murder . "
[ sighs ] Now what ?
Wait for the coast guard .
- I 'm sorry . - What for ?
Ever since you picked me up , things have been going wrong .
The clock broke , the windows have been breaking .
- The weirdo at the door last night . - That isn 't you .
I 'm not so sure .
Things seem to happen to me . I 'm bad luck .
I don 't believe in luck , good or bad .
I don 't believe in anything much .
Something did happen once .
My father was a fisherman .
He ran a trawler out of Whitely Reef .
One night , late , he was coming back in .
He was out beyond the reef , out near Spivey Point .
He looked to windward
and saw a brig under shortsail
heading right for him .
And he radioed . There was no reply .
Nothing moved on the deck , but she held her course .
My dad and two of his hands ,
they boarded the brig ... The Resa Jane .
No one was on board .
There was food on the table ... and a hot , steaming cup of coffee .
But underneath , a tin cup was rusted to the table .
And then something caught my father 's eye .
It was a gold doubloon , minted in Spain , 1867 .
My dad picked up the coin , put it in his breast pocket
of his jacket , and zippered it up .
He came home , told us the story .
And he unzippered the pocket to give me the coin .
It was gone .
I think I 'll go to Vancouver now .
" April 21st . The deed is done .
Blake followed our false fire on shore ,
and his ship broke apart on the rocks off Spivey Point .
We were aided by an unearthly fog
that rolled in as if heaven sent ,
although God had no part in our actions tonight .
Blake 's gold will be recovered tomorrow ,
but may the Lord forgive us for what we have done . "
I couldn 't read any further .
Your grandfather had a way with words .
Our celebration tonight is a travesty .
We 're honoring murderers .
[ music fades out ]
- [ slow music playing ] - [ wind blowing ]
[ man on tape ] Side one , KAB promos and lead-ins .
[ male DJ ] More music on top of the world KAB 1340 .
- [ man ] Thirty-three . - [ music playing ]
[ DJ ] KAB 1340 .
[ man ] Fifty-seven .
[ DJ ] From the top of the world ,
fabulous 1340 .
KAB , Antonio Bay .
[ man ] Thirty-one .
[ DJ ] From the top of the world , fabulous 1340 .
The smooth sound of KAB , Antonio Bay , California .
[ foghorn blowing ]
[ man ] Fifty-four .
[ DJ in a sultry voice ] KAB 1340 .
[ wind blowing loudly ]
[ man ] Thirty-one .
[ DJ in a sultry voice ] The sounds of the surf from Antonio Bay .
KAB 1340 .
[ man ] Thirty-nine .
[ DJ in an upbeat voice ] Fabulous 1340 KAB , Antonio Bay .
[ jazz jingle playing ]
More music on top of the world , KAB 1340 .
[ man ] Est-111-B , cut two .
[ DJ ] From the top of the world ,
- fabulous 1340 KAB , Antonio Bay . - [ jazz jingle playing ]
Father , where did you find this ?
My grandfather hid his sins in the walls .
- When did you find it ? - Last night ...
Just after midnight . What difference does it make ?
That 's the same time the rest of the town fell apart .
[ ominous music playing ]
[ silently ] Yes .
And the same time
the six conspirators met one hundred years ago .
It 's really getting late .
Uh , there 's not much we can do about any of this .
Are you going to give the benediction tonight , Father ?
Antonio Bay has a curse on it .
- Do we take that as a " no " ? - [ whispers ] Maybe it 's just as well .
We 're leaving now , Father .
Will you be all right ?
I 'm going to call Dr. Thayden
and ask him to just drop by .
I think you 're taking all of this much too seriously .
[ whispers ] We 're all cursed , Mrs. Williams , all of us .
- [ DJ ] 1340 KAB . - [ jazz jingle playing ]
[ man ] Forty-four .
[ DJ ] The smooth sound .
Fabulous 1340 KAB .
[ man ] Forty-five .
[ upbeat music playing ]
[ DJ ] From the top of the world , fabulous 1340 KAB ,
Antonio Bay , California .
[ Man ] Forty-six .
[ music slows and warps ]
[ DJ in a distorted voice ] The smooth sound ...
[ demonic voice ] Something that one lives with
like an albatross around the neck ,
No . More like a millstone ,
a plumbing stone , by God .
[ loudly ] Damn them all !
[ screams ]
[ tape fast-forwarding ]
[ man , high pitched and fast ] Nine .
[ DJ , high pitched and fast ] Every hour on the hour , KAB news and weather .
[ man , normal speed ] Ten .
- [ music playing ] - [ DJ , normal speed ] Every hour ,
on the hour ,
KAB news and weather .
[ man ] End side two , KAB promos .
How can a man drown and not touch the water ?
He had water in his lungs ,
salt water around his mouth ,
seaweed in his clothes .
Unless ...
You OK ?
Did you see his eyes ?
Yeah , I saw his eyes .
[ telephone ringing ]
[ shouts ] Andy , the telephone .
I got it , Mrs. Kobritz .
[ ringing continues ]
Hello ?
Andy , where did you get that piece of driftwood ?
I told you , Mom , it was on the beach this morning .
- Where ? - By the rocks .
What was it doing ?
First it was a gold coin and then it turned into the wood .
Andy , I want you to stay away from the rocks .
Do you understand ?
Don 't pick up anything else off the beach .
It didn 't belong to anybody .
I know , honey . It 's all right .
I just don 't want you to pick up anything else
unless you come and get me first . OK ?
OK .
Is Mrs. Kobritz there ?
She just came in .
OK . I have to start the broadcast now .
Andy , promise me you won 't leave the house tonight .
Oh , Mom .
Promise me .
Oh , OK .
I love you , Andy .
Me , too , Mom . Bye .
[ seagulls screeching outside ]
Ahoy , mateys .
This is Stevie Wayne , your night light ...
And KAB , Antonio Bay , California ,
is on the air .
I 've lined up some tunes to help you celebrate
the 100th birthday of Antonio Bay .
So let 's get down to business .
[ light jazz playing ]
What did your mother want , Andy ?
Nothing .
Oh , it must have been something .
Mm , nothing .
Hey , Mrs. Kobritz ,
what are those clouds out there ?
Evidence of deep penetrating wounds
in each ocular orbit entering into the cranial cavity .
Also jagged lacerations to the face ...
Do you want to wait out front ?
I 'd rather wait with you .
OK .
Thorax has been crushed ,
and the lungs are filled with fluid .
Talk to you a minute ?
Yeah .
- She gonna be all right ? - Yeah .
Did you talk to Simms ?
I got him on the radio . He 's coming back from Bodega Bay .
What the hell happened out there ?
There was rust all over everything .
It was like the boat had been out there
a long time , taking on water .
He was down below near the bunks .
Nick , his wounds are covered with algae ,
his lungs are full , and there 's silt under his fingernails .
I tell you , I saw Dick Baxter three days ago in Salinas .
Now he 's lying in there on the table
looking like he 's been underwater for a month .
- Do you feel that ? - I 'll tell you what happens .
- It just got cold in here . - You see , the water acts like ice .
[ ominous music playing ]
A whole body would take a year to decompose ,
longer if it was down far enough , cold enough .
But he was on the boat .
He was below decks .
No .
Dick Baxter died in the ocean .
[ music grows louder ]
You remember last October , those three kids that went diving
- for that old boat off the point ? - Yeah .
We got to ' em , they 'd been down for a week , maybe 10 days .
I swear to you right now ,
he 's been down longer .
[ screams ] Nick !
[ slow music playing ]
[ whimpers ]
[ foghorn blowing in distance ]
[ foghorn blowing ]
[ foghorn blowing loudly ]
- [ crickets chirping ] - [ dog barking ]
[ Mayor ] And while the wrecking of that beautiful ship
upon our coast was , of course ,
a tragedy to those who were on the ship ,
it still was the catalyst that brought together
all of the people of this wonderful area .
They came together ,
they formed the charter for Antonio Bay ,
the charter by which you have voted for these councilmen
who sit on my left and my right tonight .
[ applause ]
Kathy , the Coast Guard 's out there looking for them .
Now , they 're gonna cover the area pretty good ,
so , really , all we can do is wait .
[ instrumental music playing ]
I understand , sheriff .
Thank you .
[ Mayor from distance ] ... our 100th anniversary .
- I got to go . I 'm up next . - Yeah .
I 'm so sorry , Mrs. Williams .
It 's funny ... but all I can think about is ...
my silly dog barking all night and ,
and me just , just wishing Al would come home .
Now , we can 't have the ...
chairlady of the birthday celebration in tears , can we ?
I don 't think you ought to go out there .
Oh , I think that 's exactly what I ought to do .
I appreciate all your help , Nick .
[ silently ] That 's all right .
- [ music stops playing ] - [ applause coming from distance ]
[ music playing on the radio ]
[ Stevie on the radio ] I searched a long time for this one .
I hope you remember it .
Happy 100th , Antonio Bay .
The ceremonies are underway at Shelby Square .
And we 'll have that candlelight procession
in about an hour .
So if you hurry , you can still make it .
The coast guard dropped me a note
saying they found The Sea Grass earlier this afternoon ,
but there 's no further word as to the condition of the ship
or the men on-board .
I 'll keep you posted as the news comes in to me .
Hope no one else gets lost out there in the fog .
[ jazz continues playing on the radio ]
I 'll be right back .
[ telephone ringing ]
KAB .
Hello . My name 's Nick Castle .
You don 't know me , but I 'm one of the men
who found The Sea Grass this afternoon .
Oh , I 'm sorry .
I really don 't have any further word .
I understand .
That 's not what I called about . It 's ... uh , you just mentioned
something now on the radio about the fog .
[ ominous music playing ]
Well , this is going to sound a little strange .
I saw the fog last night out in the ocean in the distance .
It was ... glowing .
[ foghorn blowing ]
Well , what seemed to be happening is
that the wind was moving due east , and the fog just kept moving west .
I know that sounds completely crazy .
Right now it doesn 't .
Something happened last night .
At the same time that fog was moving in ,
this whole town went unglued . Hold on .
[ jazz music stops ]
[ another track starts playing ]
I 've got some more birthday music for you
and a few other surprises .
Then I 'll be ready to check in with the weatherman .
And the weatherman will be ready to check in with you .
[ ominous music playing ]
[ jazz playing on the radio ]
- Hello ? - Yeah , I 'm still here .
There 's one other thing .
It may have nothing to do with The Sea Grass .
Oh , anything .
My son found a piece of driftwood this morning .
[ foghorn blowing ]
Hey , hey , Mel . How you doing ?
Your girlfriend on the radio has been talking about you .
I came in tonight just to keep her happy .
Yeah . I thought you were off tonight .
I love my job .
Yeah , well ...
You can tell them all about that big fog bank
moving in the southeast there .
Where ?
Oh , you 'll see it . I 'm on my way . See you tomorrow .
Yeah , Mel . I 'll see you .
[ ominous music mixed with jazz on the radio ]
Ah .
There you are .
[ foghorn blowing ]
I 've got to make a run out to the lighthouse
at Spivey Point . Want to come ?
- Sure . - Come on .
[ telephone ringing ]
- KAB . - Hi , sweetheart !
I thought you were celebrating .
I couldn 't spend an evening without you .
Well , I 'm up in about 30 seconds . What 's new ?
Another fog bank .
Where ?
It 's coming in off the ocean from the southeast .
It 's heading inland . It should be here
at the weather station in 5-10 minutes .
Dan , hold on .
- [ clicks a button ] - [ music stops ]
I have a special weather bulletin .
The Tri-County Weather Station reports a fog bank
moving southeast along the coast .
For whoever 's interested ,
that 's the weather station on Old Russellville Road .
Repeating ,
a fog bank is moving southwest along the coast
toward the weather station on Old Russellville Road .
[ foghorn blowing ]
Dan , are you still there ?
I 'm still here . [ laughs ]
Hey , you , uh , sound different tonight ,
uh , kind of intense .
I just feel like talking , that 's all .
Wait a minute . I thought you told me
you didn 't like to talk on the telephone
because you talked on the radio all day .
Dan , where 's the fog now ?
Well , it should be right outside my door now .
[ slow music playing on the radio ]
Hold on . I 'm going to try something .
[ Stevie ] I can see it .
[ laughs ] Hey , now , what is the big deal ?
You 've seen fog once , you seen it for life .
No . There 's something different about this fog , Dan . It glows .
Can 't you see anything yet ?
Glows ? Oh , I get it .
You take something to keep you going , right ?
Does it make you feel a little weird sometimes ?
[ radio dies ]
- Hey . - What ?
The lights went out .
Everything 's going crazy .
Barometer 's falling , temperature 's dropping .
- Dan , what is it ? - What the hell 's that ?
Dan , what is it ? What 's happening ?
What is it ? What 's happening ?
Someone 's shining a light through the window .
Dan , listen to me .
Hold on , sweetheart . I wanna check this out .
Dan !
[ shouts ] Dan , stay on the phone !
[ pounding on door ]
This has got to be a joke .
[ sloshing ]
Someone 's at the front door , sweetheart , playing a stupid joke .
And whoever it is ... they ain 't gonna like finding me home .
Dan , stay away from the door !
Dan !
- Dan ! - [ doors open ]
Hello ?
Anybody here ?
Some asshole got drunk and started taking
this 100-year-old business too seriously .
- [ gasps ] - [ muffled ] Dan !
[ shouts ] Dan !
[ Dan grunts and shouts in pain ]
[ whispers ] Dan .
[ hangs up ]
[ stops the music ]
And so all of us living here in Antonio Bay today
owe a great debt of gratitude
to those men and women a hundred years ago
who struggled and sacrificed to make this town grow
into what it is today .
And it 's up to us to keep their kind of spirit alive .
- [ man ] Yeah . - [ applause ]
I have an urgent bulletin .
Will sheriff David Simms please contact KAB radio immediately ?
The number is 555-2131 .
This is an emergency .
[ ominous music playing ]
So we must redouble our efforts , work together .
We have a vital , thriving community .
And I say we have to keep it that way .
[ Stevie ] This is an emergency .
Sheriff David Simms , please contact KAB immediately .
555-2131 . This is an emergency .
[ Mrs. Williams talking in distance ]
[ dialing ]
[ telephone rings ]
- [ sheriff ] Hello ? - Hello ?
Hello ?
Sheriff Simms ?
And so , as we make our way to the presentation of the statue ,
I think we should all keep in mind the significance of this night
for every citizen of Antonio Bay .
[ ominous music playing ]
[ generator turbines whining ]
[ buoy bell ringing in the distance ]
We should all proceed over to the statue .
Single file . Don 't push . Take your time .
- [ ominous music playing ] - [ wind blowing ]
[ scared ] Andy !
[ groans ]
[ shouts ] Start !
[ desperately ] Please start !
[ frogs croaking ]
[ Andy ] Why did all the lights go out ?
Oh , one of the lines are probably down , Andy .
They usually take care of these things right away .
I think it 's kind of neat .
Hello ?
[ frogs croaking ]
[ frogs stop croaking ]
What 's that now ?
[ ominous music grows louder ]
[ desperately ] Start !
[ shouts ] Andy ! Andy , get out of the house !
Mrs. Kobritz , get him out of the house .
Please ! Run !
I think maybe we better close all the windows , Andy .
Are your bedroom windows closed ?
I 'll go see .
Hello ?
Someone listen to me ! My son is trapped !
887 White Beach Lane ! My son is trapped by the fog !
Andy , get out of the house ! Run !
Wow ! Look at that !
- Are your windows all closed ? - Yes , ma 'am .
I wonder about your mother 's bedroom .
[ rhythmical pounding on door ]
Please , someone ! My son is trapped !
[ Stevie on the radio ] Andy , run ! Run !
Mrs. Kobritz , run !
Andy , I want you to go to your room .
I think I should stay .
Right now . Right now .
- Yes . - Right now .
[ foghorn blowing outside ]
[ doors creaking ]
[ foghorn blowing ]
[ silently ] Go to your room .
I want to see who it is .
No .
Can 't I stay for two more seconds ?
OK , OK , I 'm going .
[ muffled sounds ]
Mrs. Kobritz ?
[ rhythmical pounding on door ]
Please . My son is trapped !
887 White Beach Lane .
Someone get to 887 White Beach Lane .
Mrs. Kobritz ?
[ wood creaking ]
[ Stevie ] My son is trapped ! Get him out of the fog !
Please , someone .
My son is trapped !
877 White Beach Lane .
Come on ! Get out of there , now !
[ Stevie ] Andy , run ! Run !
[ radio falters ]
Come on ! Come on .
Go ! Go !
[ engine revs ]
[ gears grinding ]
Come on !
Ease it , don 't pop it . Try to ease it out .
[ silently ] Oh , Jesus .
Come on , Beth ! Come on .
Come on . Come on . It 'll go . It 'll go . It 'll go .
Nick !
- Reverse ! Reverse ! - Come on !
- Come on , do it ! Do it ! - [ Elizabeth screams ]
[ music fades out ]
[ man ] ... wait for the last 20 minutes .
I think it 's best we call it a night here .
Another 5 or 10 minutes , everyone will have seen the statue .
All right , but let 's get ' em through as quickly as we can .
It 'd probably be a good idea if you went home , Kathy .
We can close up here .
I should see it through to the end .
Mrs. Williams , there 's nothing more to do here .
Let me take you home .
A little annoying , but you 're right .
- Would you please take me ? - Yes , ma 'am .
- I 'll call you tomorrow , Kathy . - OK , thank you .
[ ominous music playing ]
[ Stevie ] Andy , I don 't even know if you can hear me .
I 'm sorry that I didn 't come for you , that I wasn 't there .
Andy , please understand .
I have to stay here .
The fog ... is moving inland
away from the beach
towards Antonio Bay .
[ radio failing ] It 's over by the armory .
I can 't remember the name of the - -
No , no ... I think it 's Chestnut .
Feel like listening to some music ?
Sure .
[ Stevie ] It 's moving faster now .
Up Regent Avenue .
Up to the end of Smallhouse Road .
What 's that ?
It 's just hitting the outskirts of town .
Broad Street .
[ engine revving ]
Clay Street .
Nick !
[ dramatic music playing ]
[ Stevie ] It 's moving down 10th Street .
Get inside and lock your doors .
Close your windows .
There 's something in the fog .
If you 're on the south side of town , go north .
Stay away from the fog .
Richardsville Pike up to Beacon Hill is the only clear road .
Up to the church .
If you can get out of town , get to the old church .
Now the junction at 101 is cut off .
It 's the only place left to go .
Get to the old church on Beacon Hill .
It cut us off !
- Where is it ? - Right behind us in the driveway .
Quick , inside .
[ Nick ] Come on .
[ Mrs. Williams ] Hurry .
[ Nick ] Father ?
Is there a basement or cellar in here ?
- We can 't hide any longer . - We have to try !
No matter where we go , it will find us .
Is there a basement or cellar here , Father ?
There 's a study in back . I 'll show you the way .
Come on . Hurry .
Come on . Give me that .
[ dramatic music intensifies ]
The fog is sweeping inland .
It 's almost like a wall across the east end of town .
Blake and his men have come for us .
- Who 's Blake ? - Oh , it 's in the journal .
- What journal ? - I don 't know . It 's here somewhere .
- Father , where 's the journal ? - What are you talking about ?
- What ? - Where 's the journal ?
It 's - - It 's in there .
[ doors squeaking ]
Over by the window ?
- It can do us no good now . - It 's all we 've got .
If anything happens , just lock the door .
Get back . Shut the door .
[ doors squeaking ]
[ pounding ]
[ pounding gets closer ]
- " Six must die . " That was on the ... - The three men on the Sea Grass .
- And the weatherman is four . - [ Andy ] Mrs. Kobritz .
- Yeah , five . - And one of us makes six .
That 's what they want . They 've come back
for the six original conspirators .
- Six other lives to take the place . - There must be something in here !
- It 's me they want . I am the - - - Why would they want you ?
Wait , Father . You didn 't read us this .
Look . " Were it possible to raise the dead ,
I would return Blake 's fortune to him intact ,
save the money spent on these walls that hide it . "
" My fellow conspirators believe
that the confiscated fortune has been stolen from them ,
when in fact , I am the thief ,
and God 's Temple is the tomb of gold . "
" I am the thief , and God 's Temple is the tomb ... "
[ crash ]
Now , wait . Get - - get rid of that !
Nick !
Get out of the way !
[ pounding on door ]
[ clank ]
- Give me a hand . - Andy , stay right there .
Nick .
[ screams ]
The gold .
[ sloshing ]
He melted down the gold into this .
[ screams ]
[ Elizabeth ] Somebody help her !
- [ Nick groans ] - Nick , no !
Don 't go in there !
[ shouting in pain ]
[ wind howling ]
[ threatening music grows louder ]
Blake , I have your gold .
[ silently ] Blake ?
[ metal clanking ]
[ someone screams ]
This is your gold , Blake .
My grandfather stole it from you .
I 'm the one who must answer for it .
I 'm the sixth conspirator .
I 'm Father Malone .
Take me .
[ heavy breathing ]
[ ominous music ]
[ Stevie screams ]
Father Malone !
[ slow music playing ]
Look .
It 's going away .
[ dog barking in distance ]
[ Stevie ] I don 't know what happened to Antonio Bay tonight .
Something came out of the fog and tried to destroy us .
In one moment , it vanished .
But if this has been anything but a nightmare
and if we don 't wake up to find ourselves safe in our beds ,
it could come again .
To the ships at sea who can hear my voice ,
look across the water into the darkness .
Look for the fog .
[ doors creaking ]
Why not six , Blake ?
[ music stops ]
[ under breath ] Why not me ?
[ ominous music fades in ]